

Name: Sathia

Add: No. 56, Jalan BP 11 Taman Bukit Permata, Gombak

68100, Selangor Darul Ehsan.

Career Summary

Possess a strong foundation of corporate finance and treasury working experience. I had the opportunity to add-value to the organization with my audit experience.

<u>Skills</u>

I have past experience with Microsoft Office, PowerPoint, SAP, and Oracle with Hyperion Essbase and JD Edwards software.

Qualifications

1993 The Chartered Institute of Certified Management Accountants, UK

A member of Malaysian Institute of Accountants (MIA)

Employment Summary

Dates	Employer	Position Held
May 13 – Current	KWCPL BPO Consulting Sdn Bhd Amcorp Mall, P.J. Selangor. Ref : Dato' Bashir Sharif	Consultant
May 10 – April 13	Citibank Singapore Ltd Church St. Capital Square Centre, S'pore. Ref : Mr. Peter Wallwin Tel: +65 62255225	Credit & Risk Control Dept. Deputy Head
Sep 08 – Mar10	Inpana & Associates Chartered Accountants Kompleks Mutiara, Jalan Ipoh K.L Ref: Mr Seelan Cheliah Tel: 603 - 62051615	Senior Manager
Oct 97 – Sep 08	Sumitomo Corporation (KL) S/B Ref : Tuan Haji Nasir bin Othman Gen. Manager Tel : 6012 - 2682253	Senior Manager
Aug 94 – Sep 97	Deloitte KassimChan Chartered Accountants Ref: Mr Michael Loh Senior Partner – Japanese Corp.	Manager

Expected Income

RM14,000 and above.

Availability

Notice with two months.

Employment History

KWCPL BPO CONSULTING SDN BHD

Consultant
May 2013 – Current
Financial Advisory for Tax, Accounting and Investment.

Reporting to the Director and CEO of the Company for overall Malaysian Operation.

Principal Accountabilities:-

- Primary responsible on all clients portfolio.
- Assist clients on loan ventures with the local banks for business investment in local projects.
- Lead on due diligent for new companies prior to the acquisitions and prepare recommendation report on findings and advice to the Management on decision making on the cost of purchase consideration.
- Dealing with overseas office subsidiaries (financial controllers and consultants) on the accounting and financial matters on behalf of the clients.
- Deals with the cashflow projection for clients.
- Deals with related Corporate Tax and Withholding Tax on Advisory Consultation.
- Lead a group of 5 Finance Team to attend accounting work for clients' prior audit.

Accomplishment:-

- Accomplish to improve the credit control of a New Zealand Company branch office in Malaysia and able to collect NZD343, 000 (.>90days overdue) within 2 months after accepting the job task.
- Restructure the accounting department for a medical centre with proper coordination and improvise the IT department for more efficient reporting and all revenue data is captured in their master data system in Chennai, India office.
- Identify the negligence in capturing obsolete stock as a normal stock as part of the purchase consideration for India operations.
- Input and improvise internal control mechanism to develop efficient cost management and credit control.

CITIBANK SINGAPORE LTD

May 2010 – April 2013 Deputy Head, Credit & Risk Control Dept. (Contract)

Assist the Head to manage the Dept., including but not limited to training and supervising staff in credit & risk control.

Principal Accountabilities:-

- Lead Credit Risk Control Singapore, WB to provide efficient service and quality support for business units of WB and CB-SME.
- Devise long term development plan for the continual improvement of the operation in credit risk control to cope with business growth in line with WB strategy and goals.
- Monitor the efficiency, effectiveness and quality of the operations in the credit risk control from time to time and provide corresponding actions for improvement with respect to the changing business, customer needs or regulatory requirements.
- Liase with business units, local/group product and other supporting operation units to support capture of business opportunities in a timely and effective way.
- Ensure and implement synergies within Credit Risk Control and cooperate with other operations units to maintain the best interest of the Bank regarding risk control and resources utilization.
- Encourage and embed a culture of Compliance and ensure all staff member of CRC are aware of Group policies /procedures and standards of Money Laundering prevention procedures and controls are in place and actually followed by all staff by means of in house training programme.
 - Credit Risk Control Development.
 - o Enforce the CRC model /processes for proper implementation.
 - Act as a change agent to lead the growth of the CRC operations
 - Provide advice and consultancy services to senior management on new products and sharia compliant with respect to the operation feasibility and risk Control measure.
- Update the observation/watch-list on observation, special mentioned and risk classified credits in accordance to local and Head office guidelines, especially on the fast growing Islamic Murabaha investment commodity.
- Liase and monitor on the guidelines from Citi Islamic Investment Bank EC, Bahrain for all Islamic Treasury Hedging Solution in relation to FX forwards and Islamic cross country swaps and interest swaps based on the risk in a Sharia compliant way.
- Lead a team of 6 staffs.

Accomplishment:-

- Accomplish and managed to meet the KPI /target within 3 years in a row.
- Due to good credit risk management kept the Bank in line with the guidelines and compliance.
- Provided the Bank with accurate information and on timely reporting enable the Bank to avoid unnecessary losses.

Inpana & Associates
Chartered Accountants
Sept 2008 – March 2010
Consultant

Principal Accountabilities:-

- Dealing with Corporate Grp Finance Planning and Strategic Analysis with the Director of the Company to improve and promote Business Development.
- Provide advisory on risk mitigation, business risk for clients
- Lead on preparation on the evaluation on business liability and enable to set a limit for clients to set a respective business target.
- Experience in Debt Restructuring exercise under the Corporate Restructuring in relation to advice client respectively.
- Familiar with Takaful insurance scheme for local construction industry which specialize with Govt. projects.
- Familiar with ISO audit 2008(ISO9001:2008) incharge of setting up guidelines reference and leading a team of management staffs to execute their respective areas And job responsibilities within the statutory requirements.
- · Familiar with MASB and IFRS standards of reporting.
- Experience dealing with Co Secretary on all secretarial matters.
- Familiar with Corporate Governance and legal matters pertaining corporate Governance.
- Lead a team of 4 staffs.

Accomplishment:-

- Manage to provide financial advisory and services to clear backlog over 3 years Financials accounts within 6 months.
- Lead a team of finance team to exercise restructure of Corporate Debts of a company and currently enable the Company to sustain the Bank Loan with Financial Facilities.
- Further to that, the same company succeeded in getting high profile Govt. contracts worth more than RM300 Million.

Sumitomo Corporation (KL) Sdn Bhd Oct 97 – Sept 2008 Overseas Group Corporate Finance Section. (S.East Region) Manager

Nature of Business: Trading and manufacturing of chemicals and by products to Sumitomo group companies in Malaysia and S.East Region and other Japanese Manufacturing Companies in Malaysia and Japan.

Basic Function: Position is accountable for the ongoing analysis of process constraints, target costing projects, margin analysis, and tracing costs back to the underlying activities. Experience with job costing and process Costing.

Principal Accountabilities:-

Data Collection

- Construct data accumulation systems for a cost accounting system.
- Create and review the controls needed for data accumulation and reporting systems.

Inventory

- Coordinate physical inventory and cycle counts
- Investigate cycle counting variance and resolve issues
- Update standard costs in the bill of materials
- Review standard and actual costs for inaccuracies
- Validate the cost of goods sold as part of the month-end close.
- Accumulate and apply overhead costs as required by generally accepted accounting principles.
- Work with the materials review board to locate and dispose of obsolete inventory.

Analysis

- Conduct ongoing process constraint analyses
- Report on breakeven points by products, work centres, and factories
- Report on margins by product and division
- Report on periodic variances and their causes, focusing in particular on spending variances
- Analyze capital budgeting requests
- Perform cost accumulation tasks as a member of the target costing group.

Management and Corporate Finance Reporting

- Prepares monthly on consolidation of accounts (including branch accounts and affiliates)
- Construct and organize operation budget annually and review made on a quarterly basis.
- Familiar with treasury accounting preparation on Corporate Funding to other Branches in relation to BNM guidelines.
- Familiar with Transfer Pricing c/w Forex Dealings compliance with accounting and tax related on Forex revaluation as to realized and unrealized Forex gain or loss.
- Preparation of FX hedging to support the business transaction by using the most suitable forex tools.
- To ensure and support the Corporate Debt Financing, preparation and reporting write-ups done for the top management to review.
- Liaison with External and Internal Auditors to set a clean reporting and strictly to monitor and to avoid any violation of Company rules or statutory requirements and also tax computation analysis done on monthly accord.
- Coordination on cash flow planning forecast and review and monitoring
- Experience with local Sales Tax Exemption and Customs Regulation on import and export goods/materials.
- Maintain healthy relationship with Bankers locally and overseas office on fund control
 management and Corporate Fund outsourcing and familiar with all bank trade
 documents such as Letter of Credit, Banker's Acceptance and etc.
- Manage the Company's financial assets and liabilities and monitoring on the maturity and re-pricing schedule on current time basis

- Familiar with ISO audit 2008(ISO 9001: 2008) in charge of setting up guidelines reference and leading a team of management staffs to execute their respective areas and job responsibilities within the statutory requirements.
- Manage and assist on Debt and equity financing case to case basis on projects
- Assist on consultation to the management on adequate liquidity for working capital And investing short term excess cash.
- Implementation on new banking technologies, products and services to improve
- Advice company on inter-co cash, including co-lending, dividends and capital Injection.
- Implementation on various treasury projects such as reviewing and executing
 Systems and processes as well as reviewing and driving investment strategies.
- Assist on Region Risk Management team to analyze and reporting on trade or business status on monthly accord.
- Monitoring on overall Credit Control on all business units transaction movements and prepare evidence and detailed report for the top management on decision making on policies and collection trends.

Accomplishment:-

- Lead and assist the Tokyo, IT team in settingup SAP systems in Sumitomo Corp. KL.
- Reorganize the Trade Treasury Department within the S.East Region and as such the organization generates an addition income of RM600, 000 annually.
- A Committee member of the Risk Management team for S.East Region for setting up the Risk Management Department within the region on all trade related matters.
- The Group regional office have accomplish to achieve a higher return on investment due to the team's excellent effort on accurate evaluation and good feasibility assessment research
- After the M&A exercise done for related companies have resulted a higher profitability and revenue.

Team Force: -

- Working with a team of 6 people
- Reporting directly to the Managing Director for S.East region and General Manager of the overseas project finance department in Tokyo.

Deloitte KassimChan Chartered Accountant Aug 94 – Sep 97

Manager

- Responsible for Corporate Clients auditing.
- Manage and accomplish to complete tight deadlines.
- Experience with due diligence work on various clients.
- Major clients are Panasonic, Nippon Oil and Bank of Tokyo Mitsubishi (M) Bhd, Sumitomo Group of Companies.
- Conducted audit on fraud investigation.
- Familiar with IPO Listing and Bursa Malaysia reporting and disclosure instrument.
- Involved in Forensic Accounting services for clients.
- Lead a team of 8 staffs and report to Sr. Partner of the Firm.

Deloitte KassimChan Tax Jun 88 – Aug 94

Asst. Manager

- Organize tax planning for Corporate Clients to meet deadlines.
- Specialize in service and sales tax and also Corporate Tax.
- Involved in various projects on Mergers and Acquisitions (M&A) of Companies in Malaysia.
- Experience in Dealings with Danaharta and Debt Restructuring Exercise.
- Report to various tax managers and also on separate assignments to Partner of the Firm.
- Major clients Sime Darby Plantation and Mitsui Sumitomo Insurance Co; Berjaya Group of Companies.
- Lead a team of 3 staffs and report to the Manager and Sr. Partner of the Firm.